Guide to the Stanford University, Task Force on the Area One Requirement, Western Culture Program Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Task Force on the Area One Requirement, Western Culture Program records
1985-1989
SC0396
Stanford University. Task Force on the Area One Requirement.
2 Linear feet
Minutes, correspondence, proposals, legislation, syllabi, reports, and clippings.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1990.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Task Force, established by the Provost in September 1986, was charged with making a comprehensive review of the undergraduate curriculum requirement in Area One (cultures, ideas, and values) in light of faculty and student concerns about the inclusion of women, minorities, and non-European cultures in the curriculum.
SCOPE NOTE
The Task Force on the Area One Requirement, established by the Provost in September, 1986, was charged with making a comprehensive review of the undergraduate curriculum requirements in Area One (cultures, ideas, and values) in light of faculty and student concerns about the inclusion of women, minorities, and non-European cultures in the curriculum. These records consist of minutes, correspondence, proposals, legislation, and reports of the Task Force as well as syllabi and clippings.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Assistant Provost's Office; Stanford University. Office of the Provost.; Stanford University. Task Force on the Area One Requirement.; Cultures, Ideas, and Values.; Curriculum evaluation.; Universities and colleges--Curricula.; Western Culture Debate.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Binder 1: Charge/Meetings/Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Binder 2: Drafts/Legislation/TFAOR Member Proposal (Box 1)
  - Binder 3: Background Information (Box 1)
  - Binder 4: Syllabi 1985-1989 (Box 1)
  - Binder 5: Attachments (Box 1)
  - Binder 1: Newspaper Clippings (5/86-11/87), 1986 - 1987 (Box 2)
  - Binder 2: " " (11/87-7/88), 1987 - 1988 (Box 2)
  - Binder 3: " " (11/88-1989), 1988 - 1989 (Box 2)
  - Folder: CIV Clippings (1986-1988) (Box 2)
  - Binder 1: World Civilization COurses--other Universities (Box 3)
  - Binder 2: Report Summarizing Western CUlture Programs and Debate (Box 3)
  - Binder 3: Faculty/Student/Outside Opinions (Box 3)